<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Monologue</title>
    <description>The voices of Mono</description>
    <link>http://dunno.com/</link>
    <docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss</docs>
    <generator>Monologue worker: b-diddy powerd</generator>
    <item>
      <title>01 Oct 2003: Grudge match</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;center&gt;
        &lt;a href="../images/IMG_0628.JPG" border="0"&gt;&lt;img
        src="../images/IMG_0628_TB.JPG"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;My dad and I
        
        &lt;center&gt;
        &lt;img
        src="http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/images/bowie_ticket.jpg"&gt;
        &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#10%2F01%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#10%2F01%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 Oct 2003: SouceGear is done!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We completed the &lt;a
	href="http://www.ximian.com/about_us/press_center/press_releases/index.html?pr=sourcegear"&gt;SouceGear&lt;/a&gt;
	project!

	&lt;p&gt;The project included adding a lot of functionality to Mono
	to support Web Services on the client (mostly having a full
	XmlSerializer implementation as well as its close family
	members) and making Mono robust.

	&lt;p&gt;To make sure that Mono was robust, SourceGear designed a
	series of extensive tests that Mono would be put under, and
	the acceptance criteria for the work we did included running
	the tests for a 24 hour period of time on a single instance of
	the virtual machine.  Needless to say, making the Mono VM
	robust enough to run these tests for 24 hours was not easy,
	and we ran into all sorts of low-level interesting features,
	memory leaks, race conditions and other assorted small
	problems that would not have shown under normal
	circumstances.  We are very happy about this.

	&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, while parts of the team were tracking down
	the elusive bugs in the runtime, Lluis took the time to
	implement the server side component of ASP.NET, so as part of
	the SourceGear effort, we also got our web services stack
	implement on the server, which was a nice plus.
	
&lt;h3&gt;More on exceptions&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I was feeling that I should argue a bit more about
	exceptions, until I received a mail from Krzysztof Cwalina at
	Microsoft, he raises a good point about exceptions and the
	null return pattern: they do not allow an error to be
	propagated, nor details about the error.

	&lt;p&gt;He is absolutely right, and my example with files was not a
	good one.  I had in mind APIs that did not need to propagate a
	rich error or details about the condition.  Krzysztof said:

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
	One problem with null is that you may get notified about the problem
	really far away from the point when the error occurred. Exception will
	be thrown right there at the point where the error occurs. The other
	problem is that null cannot tell you why the error occurred. Error codes
	have their own set of problems.

	&lt;p&gt;Of course (as with every design) it's a tradeoff. In this case a
	tradeoff between better error reporting (fail fast, rich error message)
	and performance (and other things). In general, we err on the side of
	better reliability, clarity of errors, etc. when designing the
	Framework. We have several exceptions to the general rule in explicitly
	identified performance-sensitive APIs.
	&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;IXmlSerializable explained&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://primates.ximian.com/~lluis/blog"&gt;Lluis&lt;/a&gt;
	the man behind the Mono implementation of Remoting and Xml
	Serializer explains on his &lt;a
	href="http://primates.ximian.com/~lluis/blog/archives/000130.html"&gt;latest
	blog entry&lt;/a&gt; how the undocumented IXmlSerializable interface
	works.  If you ever wondered how you could have precise
	control over the Xml mapping in XmlSerializer, this is the
	interface used internally by the framework.

&lt;h3&gt;Welcome Sebastien Pouliot and Duncan Mak!&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Sebastien, the man behind the Mono cryptographic
	infrastructure now has his &lt;a
	href="http://pages.infinit.net/ctech/poupou.html"&gt;own
	blog&lt;/a&gt;.

	&lt;p&gt;Duncan also started &lt;a
	href="http://primates.ximian.com/~duncan/blog/"&gt;his&lt;/a&gt; 
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#10%2F01%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#10%2F01%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Improved XmlCachingResolver</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across Chris Lovett's &lt;a
href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/en-us/dnxmlnet/html/XMLToolsUpdate.asp?frame=true#xmltoolsupdate_topic7"&gt;XmlCachingResolver&lt;/a&gt;. However,
in its current form, this tool did not meet all my needs, so I decided
to program an enhanced version of the tool.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chris' version, he simply uses the &lt;a
href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/en-us/cpref/html/frlrfsystemxmlxmlurlresolverclasstopic.asp"&gt;XmlUrlResolver&lt;/a&gt;
to download the URL given, and then stores the resulting stream into
what basically amounts to a MemoryStream. He then stores the stream in
a Hashtable, and gives a reference to it. When the same document is
requested in the future, he seeks to 0 in the MemoryStream and returns
it again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has many problems. Firstly, because the same MemoryStream is
returned each time, it is not thread safe, making it nearly useless
for ASP.NET applications. Secondly, the cache is not persisted between
creations of the XmlCachingResolver, meaning that each time an
application using it is started up, the XML must be downloaded
again. Third, his tool does not account for instances where the XML
might change (such as when loading an XML document, not a DTD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my requirements for an improved version were pretty clear: 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save my cache to disk, not in memory&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;When given an HTTP URL, use If-Modified-Since to see if the document needs to be downloaded again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created some code that does exactly this. The code creates a
cache inside the temporary folder, and holds the downloaded
items. When the a document is requested, the new XmlCachingResolver
checks if the request is an HTTP request. If so, it will a see if it
has been stored in the cache. If not, it will download the item from
the web server and cache the result. If it is in the cache folder, the
last modification time of the file is sent as the If-Modified-Since
header. If the item is not modified, the cached version is returned,
otherwise the cache is updated.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download my code &lt;a href="http://codeblogs.ximian.com/blogs/benm/archives/samples/Mono.Xml.XmlCachingResolver.zip"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The code is under
the X11 license. It includeds a sample that will create an XmlReader from
a given URL 5 times. If you use a packet sniffer, you will see that
only once is the full body downloaded (and if you run it again, the
full body will only be downloaded if the document has changed).&lt;/p&gt;
 </description>
      <link>http://codeblogs.ximian.com/blogs/benm/archives/000039.html</link>
      <author>Ben Maurer</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="False">39@http://codeblogs.ximian.com/blogs/benm/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 19:14:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why DTM XPathDocument Rocks</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Atsushi, the XML super-hacker, implemented our &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/default.asp?url=/library/en-us/cpref/html/frlrfsystemxmlxpathxpathdocumentclasstopic.asp"
/&gt;XPathDocument&lt;/a&gt;.  At first, his design is non-intuitive, and looks
as if it would hurt performance, however with careful consideration
its great design becomes apparent.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, XML has been represented using the DOM API. The DOM
represents XML as a huge linked tree of nodes. This model gives equal
treatment to reading and writing to the tree. Reading consists of
traversing the linked lists inside the object representation of the
tree, while writing consists of adding a new object to the linked
list. However, the model comes with a huge disadvantage: memory
overhead. In Mono, every instance of System.Object takes up a
&lt;em&gt;minimum&lt;/em&gt; of eight bytes. Take the XML
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;item&gt;Apples&amp;lt;/item&gt;&lt;/code&gt;. In the DOM this is represented
as an Element class, which probably takes up 50 or more bytes to
describe the element (name, prefix, namespace, first child, last
child, first attribute, etc) and a Text element, which probably takes
up about 12 bytes (not including the string value). This is far more
than the amount of space in the string
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;item&gt;Apples&amp;lt;/item&gt;&lt;/code&gt;! Even worse, each one of these
objects must be tracked by the Garbage Collector, which will try to
find out if there are any dead references inside the tangled mess that
was once a clean, beautiful string. Furthermore, due to the linked
list structure of the DOM, nodes can be scattered around memory in any
order. Thus, the big caches on todays processors are negated as nodes are
retrieved from all over memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider that in most instances there is no need to write
to the tree of XML, usually it is just read from a file and never
written to. In this case, none of the benefits of the linked list
structure are realized. Microsoft created the XPathNavigator API in
order to solve this problem. Their XSLT and XPath implementations use
this class to navigate XML. Instead of being based on a tree, it is
based on a cursor that points to a location on the XML tree. For
example, when evaluating the XPath expression &lt;code&gt;a/b/c&lt;/code&gt;
MoveToFirstChild () will be called, and a do...while (MoveToNext ())
loop will be executed looking for an element with the local-name a,
then a b child node will be looked for, etc. The preferred provider of
XPathNavigators is XPathDocument (you can also create a XPathNavigator
wrapper around XmlDocument). Microsoft's XPathDocument, however, is
merely a lightweight DOM, it still holds all the old problems of
over-allocation.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Atsushi used an innovative solution to remedy the problem. It is key
to note that the XPathNavigator &lt;em&gt;does not require&lt;/em&gt; the XML to
be represented as a linked list, it would be possible (though
inefficient) to create a version that just read from the file on
demand. Atsushi picked a compromise between these two
extremes. Atsushi's version represents the document as a table of
nodes, represented as a set of parallel arrays. These arrays can be
thought as holding the exact same data as the classes in Microsoft's
navigator. However, because the arrays are of primitive types, they do
not incur the object allocation overhead. Furthermore, the links
between nodes are just integer pointers to indexes in the array of
nodes. The garbage collector does not understand this type of link,
and is not forced to follow the tree. It only tracks the actual
XPathDocument objects and the arrays it holds.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So how much difference does this make? According to Atsushi, "it
navigates nearly 10 times faster than XPathNavigator created by
XmlDocument.CreateNavigator(), and even 5 times faster than that of
XPathDocument [from MS.NET 1.0]." Recently, I asked Atsushi to
redesign DTM using arrays of structs, rather than parallel arrays. It
reduces the cost of cloning the XPathNavigator, an operation
frequently used by XPath. From the testing I have done with the new
version, this benefit can easily be seen in XSLT and XPath.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://codeblogs.ximian.com/blogs/benm/archives/000036.html</link>
      <author>Ben Maurer</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="False">36@http://codeblogs.ximian.com/blogs/benm/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2003 02:37:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Sep 2003: Anders Hejlsberg</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview Anders said: 

	&lt;blockquote cite="Anders Hejlsberg"&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;If you ask beginning programmers to write a calendar control, they
	often think to themselves, "Oh, I'm going to write the world's best
	calendar control! It's going to be polymorphic with respect to the
	kind of calendar. It will have displayers, and mungers, and this,
	that, and the other." They need to ship a calendar application in two
	months. They put all this infrastructure into place in the control,
	and then spend two days writing a crappy calendar application on top
	of it. They'll think, "In the next version of the application, I'm
	going to do so much more."

	&lt;p&gt;Once they start thinking about how they're actually going to
	implement all of these other concretizations of their abstract
	design, however, it turns out that their design is completely
	wrong. And now they've painted themself into a corner, and
	they have to throw the whole thing out. I have seen that over
	and over. I'm a strong believer in being minimalistic. Unless
	you actually are going to solve the general problem, don't try
	and put in place a framework for solving a specific one,
	because you don't know what that framework should look like.
	[&lt;a href="http://www.artima.com/intv/handcuffs.html"&gt;Artima's
	interview with Anders&lt;/a&gt;]
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I like Anders' position regarding Checked Exceptions,
	contrast this with James Gosling's statement, which I believe
	does paint a broken picture:

	&lt;blockquote cite="James Gosling"&gt;
	One of the traditional things to screw up in C code is opening
	a data file to read. It's semi-traditional in the C world to
	not check the return code, because you just know the file is
	there, right? So you just open the file and you read it. But
	someday months from now when your program is in deployment,
	some system administrator reconfigures files, and the file
	ends up in the wrong place. Your program goes to open the
	file. It's not there, and the open call returns you an error
	code that you never check. You take this file descriptor and
	slap it into your file descriptor variable. The value happens
	to be -1, which isn't very useful as a file descriptor, but
	it's still an integer, right? So you're still happily calling
	reads. And as far as you can tell, the world is all rosy,
	except the data just isn't there. [&lt;a
	href="http://www.artima.com/intv/solid.html"&gt;Artima's
	interview with James Gosling&lt;/a&gt;]
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;This is in fact the source of many security problems.  One
	of the first security code audits I witnessed was by a
	volunteer that reviewed my first setuid application that I
	shipped as part of the Midnight Commander (the software only
	shipped after the security audit).  A 200 line program got
	back 700 lines worth of comments, many of them related to not
	checking error conditions from trivial system calls like
	`close()'.

	&lt;p&gt;But modern C APIs do not use int return codes, in fact not
	even the C standard library uses those: that is only the
	low-level Unix C API that has this feature.  The standard C
	library API returns a FILE * object, and for instance, most of
	Gtk+ and Gnome &lt;a
	href="http://developer.gnome.org/doc/API"&gt;APIs&lt;/a&gt; return
	objects (in the form of a pointer to an object).

	&lt;p&gt;The beauty of returning a pointer to an object, is that you
	can return NULL as your standard error return value, and if
	the value mattered, you will most likely take the necessary
	steps to check its return value, or they application will just
	crash the moment you try to use it.

	&lt;p&gt;This could be applied to the .NET and Java APIs to reduce
	the amount of required try/catchs.  For example, the
	File.IO.OpenRead method could be (shown here is the artist's
	representation):

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre id="code"&gt;
	public static FileStream OpenRead (string file)
	{
		int fd = open (file);
		
		if (f == -1)
			return null;
		return new FileStreamFromFD (f);
	}&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Which makes null a valid return value.  If you fail to
	check for the return value, you would get a nice
	NullReferenceException, but you would allow the expensive
	creation of an exception object, and the ugly try/catch block
	in the call site.

	&lt;p&gt;Obviously we can not change the existing APIs, but we could
	encourage developers to minimize their use of exceptions.  In
	my limited personal experience with software design, when I
	have faced applications with tons of Exceptions it was
	extremely hard to keep up with them.  A rewrite of the
	software to avoid exceptions and use the more sane
	API paid for. 
	
&lt;h3&gt;More Mono Bloggers&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I wrote about Ben previously, he now has a &lt;a
	href="http://codeblogs.ximian.com/blogs/benm/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; which
	we are hosting for him at Ximian.

</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F29%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F29%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;a href="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/activity-log.php"&gt;Miguel de Icaza&lt;/a&gt; was kind enough to get me a blog on the &lt;a href="http://www.ximian.com"&gt;Ximian&lt;/a&gt; server, so I should probably make use of it. I am a &lt;a href="http://go-mono.com"&gt;Mono&lt;/a&gt; hacker, currently focusing on Managed XSLT, XML Performance, and working on our home-brewed documentation browser (and now editor), Monodoc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://codeblogs.ximian.com/blogs/benm/archives/000035.html</link>
      <author>Ben Maurer</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="False">35@http://codeblogs.ximian.com/blogs/benm/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2003 23:15:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Sep 2003: Productive day</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
            Had a pretty productive day on the mono front. Working on
            getting PythonNet building with our tools. So far this has
            entailed a bunch of monodis patches (I'd show you them but
            it would involve walking into the other room and turning
            sshd on), and implementing pinvoke in ilasm. The PythonNet
            runtime is written in C# but it uses monodis/ilasm to
            convert callbacks calling conventions to cdecl using
            modopt. This technique is also being used in
            System.Drawing for interop with an existing library
            (libjpeg I think). There was talk of this being done in
            Gtk somewhere too. I dont know if that ever happened.
&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
            Had to force myself to go to bed early. I did cheat and
            bring the laptop with me but I only have battery power. So
            I am laying in bed with my dog, my laptop, and a
            beer. Doesn't get any better then this ;-)...check that,
            it would be better if I had sshd running, and could access
            my music.
&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
            Mono hacker Martin has started a &lt;a
            href="http://primates.ximian.com/~martin/blog/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.
            Interesting reading. Mainly about his work on gmcs. I
            wonder if Martin wrote his own blogging tool? That would
            be classic.
&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
            So I just checked out miguel's &lt;a
            href="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/activity-log.php"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;
            and he has this cool new "Mono Blogs" section (warning
            probably doesnt work in internet explorer to take full
            advantage please click &lt;a
            href="http://www.mozilla.org/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that lists all of
            the mono hackers with blogs. We need to get our advanced
            LameBlog technology into CVS. A TODO list would be good
            too.
&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
            OK hopefully the &lt;a
            href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.txt"&gt;GPL&lt;/a&gt; will
            put me to sleep. Usually does. Lawyers must have to take
            lots of naps, this stuff is so boring.
&lt;p&gt;
            
&lt;p&gt;
            
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F27%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F27%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Sep 2003: Assembling life</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Laura and myself have been shopping for various items for
	our new appartment.  Once we had chosen the rug, everything
	fell into place, and in two hours we swiftly sorted out our
	color differences.  The rug really ties the room together.

&lt;h3&gt;New Mono Bloggers&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;a href="http://primates.ximian.com/~martin/blog/"&gt;Martin
	Baulig&lt;/a&gt; now has a blog.  He talks mostly about his work on
	the C# compiler.  He is not lucky enough to be using my
	LameBlog technology.
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F27%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F27%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Sep 2003: My new shirt is boss yo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    Just bought a new &lt;a
    href="http://www.gnu.org/gear/FSFS-tshirt.html"&gt;shirt&lt;/a&gt; from the
    FSF (and made a donation). If everyone else did the same the world
    would be a better place :-).
&lt;p&gt;
    
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F25%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F25%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Sep 2003: Madrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just coming back from the &lt;a
	href="http://congreso.hispalinux.es"&gt;HispaLinux congress&lt;/a&gt;
	in Madrid.  This was a very short trip: only two days in
	Madrid, traveled all this and did not have enough time to eat
	enough ham.

	&lt;p&gt;Update on Extremadura from Jose: they are 100,000 Linux
	desktop machines in the administration and 276 machines on
	public centers.   The public machines are fewer than the 1,500
	from the Telecentros, but still a healthy number.

&lt;h3&gt;Try Ximian Desktop 2&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The fine folks in &lt;a
	href="http://metadistros.hispalinux.es"&gt;Spain&lt;/a&gt; have a &lt;a
	href="http://metadistros.hispalinux.es/tiki-index.php?page=gnome2-live"&gt;Live
	CD with Ximian Desktop 2.&lt;/a&gt;   You can try Ximian Desktop
	without installing Linux on your machine, the whole system
	runs from a CD.

&lt;h3&gt;OpenOffice gets .NET support&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Federico pointed me to the announcement of OpenOffice's
	support for C# and the CLI, it is &lt;a
	href="http://www.openoffice.org/servlets/ReadMsg?msgId=832179&amp;listName=announce"&gt;here:&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
	We are pleased to provide a preview of the CLI-UNO language binding. It 
	gives developers the possibility to write client programs for 
	OpenOffice.org, as well as stand-alone UNO applications, with CLI 
	languages, such as C# and VB.NET.
	&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The details about the language binding are here: &lt;a
	href="http://udk.openoffice.org/cli/cli-uno.html"&gt;http://udk.openoffice.org/cli/cli-uno.html&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;h3&gt;PDC&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft PDC program is getting more and more
	interesting.  As a sneak preview of the table of contents of a
	System.Xml/System.Data based book &lt;a
	href="http://www.daveandal.net/books/8391/8391-intro-toc.htm"&gt;shows&lt;/a&gt;.
	Dare also sent me a link to the &lt;a
	href="http://www.daveandal.net/books/8960/8960-intro-toc.htm"&gt;ASP.NET&lt;/a&gt;
	changes.  Fantastic!
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F24%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F24%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Sep 2003: Visualizing and Voting</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.chrisgates.net/irv/"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a description of
instant runoff voting in Flash. This describes the
voting system I think we should use and it describes it visually,
something I think we should do more often. 
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Whoever came up with &lt;a href="http://www.findarticles.com/cf_0/m2519/4_21/62410241/p1/article.jhtml?term="&gt;push polling&lt;/a&gt; is a genius. Slimy and evil, but
also a genius. I wonder if any big corporations use push polling
tactics against their competitors?
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;div style="margin-left: 1cm; margin-right:1cm;
             background: #c0d0ff; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;
             padding: 1px; border-style: solid; border-width: 1px;"&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Ring, Ring...&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Consumer:&lt;/b&gt; Hello
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Operator:&lt;/b&gt; Hello ma'am we are running an independent survey on
             soft drinks. Would you be willing to answer some
             questions for us?
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Consumer:&lt;/b&gt; Umm, sure.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Operator:&lt;/b&gt; Thank You. Would you be more or less likely to drink
             Pepsi if you knew it was made of mashed up kitten skulls?
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Consumer:&lt;/b&gt;Less, is that true?
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Operator:&lt;/b&gt;Thank you ma'am, have a good night.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;click&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F24%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F24%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Sep 2003: More books</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
      Maybe I will just buy lots of books instead of a new TV. Today I
      gave amazon.ca some money and in a few days they will give me &lt;a
      href="http://www.amazon.ca/exec/obidos/ASIN/0060528370/702-7240094-1806424"&gt;the
      other side of the story&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      Allot of people ask me what .NET is. &lt;a
      href="http://www.microsoft.com/net/basics/framework.asp"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt;
      is a decent description.
&lt;p&gt;
      
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F22%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F22%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Sep 2003: Bitch slappin bugs</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
       Today I fixed my section header problem in PEAPI. I had been
       avoiding this bug for a few weeks but after a long night of
       reading &lt;i&gt;Lies&lt;/i&gt; I decided to take it on. Al Franken's
       sarcasm inspired me to take on section headers face to
       face. I bitch slapped them the same way he bitch slapped
       Bernie Goldberg. So what does this bitch slapping mean to the
       average dude on the street? Well the average dude off the
       street can now CVS update their ilasm tree and start using
       .data in their il code. I bet allot of people will be calling
       in sick tommorow so they can stay home and enjoy the fruits of
       my labour.
&lt;p&gt;
       &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
       .data in ilasm is very very sneaky. You can put a .data
       definition in a class definition or make it global. The sneaky
       thing is that IT IS ALL GLOBAL! If you put a .data definition
       in a class you can reference it from another class without
       using any scope resolution. Here is an example:
&lt;p&gt;
       &lt;div style="margin-left: 1cm; margin-right:1cm;
             background: #c0d0ff; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;
             padding: 1px; border-style: solid; border-width: 1px;"&gt;
     &lt;pre&gt;
.class public Stub extends [mscorlib]System.Object {
       .data some_data = int32 (1)
}
.class public T extends [mscorlib]System.Object {
        .field private static int32 some_field at some_data
}
     &lt;/pre&gt;
     &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     Crazyness, eh? As you can see Stub::some_data is being referenced
     from T::some_field without using Stub::. Thats because some_data
     is actually global.
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     Wrote a five minute hack today that reduces memory consumption in
     jay pretty drastically. Hopefully it gets approved...hint hint ;-)
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     Oh Ben, forgot to mention this this morning when we were talking
     about parsing. EOF. How you like them apples.
&lt;p&gt;
     
&lt;p&gt;
       
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F21%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F21%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Sep 2003: Lluis has a blog</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lluis, the developer behind Mono's XML Serialization, a
	large part of Remoting and our SOAP web services stack has
	started a &lt;a
	href="http://primates.ximian.com/~lluis/blog/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.  His
	first post is about the his &lt;a
	href="http://primates.ximian.com/~lluis/blog/archives/000120.html"&gt;GenXS&lt;/a&gt;
	tool used to create custom XmlSerializers (a feature not found
	on Microsoft's edition, but that we use in a few places).
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F20%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F20%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Sep 2003: Broken test cases (please)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        Sometimes broken test cases that never pass are a really good
        thing. They force you to really think through your code and
        find other bugs that your test didnt even cover. Eventually
        after you have tracked down every possible point of failure
        and are considering quitting programming and getting a job at
        McDonalds you will probably (hopefully) notice that your test
        is broken. Some of the most buried bugs I have fixed have been
        because of a broken test case. So what we need is a test
        runner that fails randomly, but we cant know that it fails
        randomly. If we knew the testing framework failed randomly we
        would just assume every test failure was a random
        failure....anyone on the Nant team willing to work on this? If
        you are dont tell me ;-).
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        Mono hacker Lluis started a &lt;a
        href="http://primates.ximian.com/~lluis/blog/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and
        already posted an interesting entry on creating custom xml
        serializers. Hopefully more of the Mono hackers (Gonzalo) that
        have an in-depth knowledge of .NET will start blogs. 
        
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        I started to write an application that converts the whitespace
        programming langauge to ilasm. It is about 90% of the way done
        but is low priority and has been back burnered. If
        you want the code send me an email.
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        Maybe its just the conspiracy theorist in me but sometimes I
        think Sun is behind this whole SCO debacle. &lt;a
        href="http://news.com.com/2452-7344-5079251.html"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt;
        quote is taken a little out of context but I cant find the
        full interview anymore. I guess I should watch the trees for
        snipers tonight ;-).
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        As I begin to leave the house I receive a backlog of 17
        pages. Guess I get to play ops for a little while. Tempted to
        leave the pager in Roxys possession.
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        I bought three new books today. Amazingly enough one of them
        is a non-technical book. &lt;i&gt;Lies&lt;/i&gt; by Al Franken. Very good
        book so far. I also got an Emacs book (not RMS's) and a intro
        to Pascal book. Its obvious enough why I got the emacs book. I
        use emacs for 95% of my computer activities but am not really
        much of a power user. The reasoning behing the pascal book is:
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;You cant get 5 pages into a compiler book without
                seeing pascal&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Oberon is a member of the pascal family&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;It was only 5 dollars&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        
        
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F20%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F20%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Sep 2003: Please open your text books to chapter 11</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        The fault block and finally block cant coexist with other SEH
        blocks. If you create a try catch finally block in C# what you
        are really getting is this:
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;div style="margin-left: 1cm; margin-right:1cm;
             background: #c0d0ff; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;
             padding: 1px; border-style: solid; border-width: 1px;"&gt;
             &lt;pre&gt;
 .try {
         .try {
                 // do some stuff
         } catch [mscorlib]System.Exception {
                 // handle exception
         }
 } finally {
         // do some stuff
 }
 &lt;/pre&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F17%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F17%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Sep 2003: Binary XML.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a
	href="http://www.kuro5hin.org/user/Carnage4Life/diary"&gt;Dare&lt;/a&gt;
	linked to &lt;a
	href="http://www.gazitt.com/OhmBlog/PermaLink.aspx/13178f4f-b851-4568-972b-2886048490a2"&gt;Omri's&lt;/a&gt;
	posting about why binary serialization for XML is a bad idea.

	&lt;p&gt;I have not really formed an opinion, and am definitely not
	an expert on the matter of binary serialization for XML, but I
	believe that Omri's position is an incorrect one.  Omri's
	thesis is that there are multiple things that you might want
	to opmize for: size, parsing speed and overhead for generating
	the data and that it is not possible to define a file format
	that satisfies all of those different needs.

	&lt;p&gt;This is not new, and this happens with everything we build
	today: as software developers we constantly have to balance
	multiple needs: maintainability, performance, extensibility,
	perfection, scalability, configurability, usability.  The job
	of an architect is precisely to find a good balance taking
	input from multiple sources.  We are going to make mistakes,
	every step of the way, but the sooner we start making those
	mistakes, the earlier we will be able to collect real data on
	the issues at hand.

	&lt;p&gt;The other problem with Omri's thesis is that it misses one
	bit: who are those likely to benefit from a binary format?
	They probably will fall in two camps: those who want smaller
	chunks of data transfered, and those who want faster
	encoding/decoding of the infoset not the average XML user.

	&lt;p&gt;We do not need to satisfy everyone, just a large percentage
	of the user base.  The others can feel free to define a
	different format, or ignore this solution altogether or build
	on top of this in the future.

	&lt;p&gt;For instance TCP/IP makes no guarantees on quality of
	service despite the fact that many people have valid and
	important uses for it.  Still, it did serve a large community
	of people and what is even more interesting: clever people
	found ways to work with these limitations and do a reasonable
	job given the foundation.  
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F16%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F16%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Sep 2003: Best Xml tool ever</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;a href="http://www.xmlhack.com/read.php?item=2061"&gt;nXML&lt;/a&gt;
      mode is very nice. I wish more tools were like this. Fast,
      simple, and easy to install.
      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Taking Roxy to &lt;a
      href="http://www.britishcolumbia.com/ParksAndTrails/Parks/details/?ID=457"&gt;Thetis
      Lake Park&lt;/a&gt;. I am going to take the camera and hope I can get
      a cool dog-in-mid-air-jumping-into-water picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
      Sunset pictures are such a cop-out....so are dog pictures. So
      here are some:
      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;a href="../images/IMG_0601.JPG"&gt;&lt;img
      src="../images/IMG_0601_tb.JPG" border="0"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
       &lt;a href="../images/IMG_0602.JPG"&gt;&lt;img
      src="../images/IMG_0602_tb.JPG" border="0"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
       &lt;a href="../images/IMG_0607.JPG"&gt;&lt;img
      src="../images/IMG_0607_tb.JPG" border="0"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      
      
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F14%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F14%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Sep 2003: XSLT in Mono: the story of a young hacker.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, I spoke to Daniel Veillard the author of &lt;a
	href="http://www.xmlsoft.org/"&gt;Libxslt and Libxml&lt;/a&gt;.  When
	Mono started, we wanted to reuse as code as possible, and
	those two libraries made a lot of sense to reuse.

	&lt;p&gt;The problem is that .NET Framework defines three mechanism
	for handling Xml: the Dom model, the pull parser, and the path
	navigator (a DOM-like &lt;i&gt;interface&lt;/i&gt;).  It was not possible
	for us to just use libxml to implement our Xml needs, it would
	have added too much overhead, and would have been an ugly
	hack.

	&lt;p&gt;.NET contains two pretty clever tricks: the pull parser
	(XmlTextReader and XmlTextWriter) and the path navigator,
	which exposes a cursor-based navigation interface.  The
	beauty of the interface is that you can wrap any kind of data
	source and expose it to the XML subsystem with this interface.
	So you can wrap a database, a comma separated value file, a
	file system, anything you can think of, and dynamically
	provide the content.  Interesting because it is possible to
	use XPath queries on top of it, or apply xslt
	transformations.  XSLT in .NET is built completely on top of
	the XPathNavigator.

	&lt;p&gt;For a long time, in Mono we used libxslt: we would dump all
	the data from an XmlDocument, or a XPathNavigator into a
	temporary file, and then use libxslt to do the heavy lifting.

	&lt;p&gt;This approach had various problems: libxslt was not designed
	to be thread safe (a requirement for us: on ASP.NET we need to
	be able to do xslt transformations from multiple threads), so
	we had to add big locks around the xslt invocations.  Also, it
	was not possible to create a context for the transformation,
	so extension functions were global to all the
	transformations.  The only solution was to shutdown and
	restart the libxslt engine every time we did a transformation,
	not really optimal.

	&lt;p&gt;Fixing the problem was not going to be easy.  Libxslt is a
	very large piece of code, and Daniel estimated that
	re-implementing it would take about a year.  That is why I
	discouraged 16-year old Mono developer Ben Maurer from working
	on this project.  He was not really ready to spend a year of
	hairy coding, and would likely not be able to do something
	even as fast as Libxslt.

	&lt;p&gt;Ben ignored my advise and went on to implement a managed
	implementation of XSLT.  The idea was to remove the libxsl
	dependency: remove the temporary files, fix the extension
	object problem, and the locks.

	&lt;p&gt;In the course of a couple of weeks this summer, Ben had the
	basics of XSLT done, and he recruited the help of Atsushi to
	help with problems and missing features in the XML core, and
	Piers to fix and improve our XPath implementation.

	&lt;p&gt;The three hacker team in less than a month did a tremendous
	amount of progress implementation was able to be used instead
	of Libxslt for Monodoc.

	&lt;p&gt;The surprising news this week is that Ben has made Mono's
	managed XSLT faster than the C-based libxslt. Faster on a
	number of the XSLTMark tests and on other practical
	stylesheets (including the stylesheet used in Monodoc).  The
	performance can be attributed partially to some performance
	improvements Atsushi did to our handling of XPathDocuments.
	The other part was the tireless work of Ben in doing
	performance tuning in our implementation: from profile-driven
	changes like removing calls to foreach on ArrayLists with
	loops to architectural changes.  The biggest improvement was
	adding an interface for resolving functions/variables at
	compile time.

	&lt;p&gt;Atsushi mentioned that lots of the performance
	improvements came from Ben reusing concepts from SAXON.  SAXON
	is the fastest xslt implementation out there, and its written
	in Java. 

	&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to all the Mono XML crazy hackers for
	achieving this fantastic progress in so little time.

&lt;h3&gt;Oberon in Mono&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The Mono IL assembler has finally matured to the point
	where it can be used to bootstrap the Oberon IL compiler on
	Mono.  The details are in &lt;a
	href="http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/"&gt;Jackson's
	Blog&lt;/a&gt;.

	&lt;p&gt;Of course, some of you might want to laugh because we got
	generics support before Oberon worked ;-)
	
	&lt;p&gt;Go Jackson!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Jakarta and Mono&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a
	href="http://www.burtongroup.com/weblogs/annethomasmanes/"&gt;Anne&lt;/a&gt;
	talks about our recent discussion.  She wants to reuse the
	Mono CLI, and build on top of it patent-free technologies
	along the lines of the technologies done in the past for Java
	(Cocoon, Struts).

	&lt;p&gt;She is absolutely right about the need to build a parallel
	universe of technologies.  In Mono we have already started
	this process:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;img src="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/tmp/map.png"&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F14%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F14%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Sep 2003: P/Invoke limitations</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jprl.com/~jon/"&gt;Jonathan Pryor&lt;/a&gt; has
	written a tutorial about Marshaling on Mono and the .NET
	Framework.  Hopefully this will become a chapter on the &lt;a
	href="http://www.go-mono.com:8080"&gt;Mono Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;One of the points discussed on the document is about string
	marshalling in .NET and the limitation imposed by the current
	specification.  Sadly the ECMA specification (and .NET) only
	cover Ansi and Unicode as encodings for strings.   Both are
	also underspecified, they are both `platform independent
	encodings'.

	&lt;p&gt;This is a problem, because there is no such thing as
	`Unicode encoding'.  There are specific ways of encoding:
	utf-8, utf-16, ucs-2, ucs-4 and others.  Which one are we
	talking about.
	
	&lt;p&gt;The issue we face on Unix and Windows is that there are
	plenty of libraries that have very specific requirements.  We
	first ran into this problem with the Python bindings to .NET.
	Python can be compiled to either use utf-8 or ucs-4 API entry
	points.  

	&lt;p&gt;Another example is &lt;a
	href="http://gtk-sharp.sf.net"&gt;Gtk#&lt;/a&gt;.  Currently it
	generates bindings like this:

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre id="code"&gt;
[DllImport("libgtk-win32-2.0-0.dll")]
static extern void gtk_label_set_text(IntPtr raw, string str);

public string Text { 
	set {
		gtk_label_set_text(Handle, value);
	}
}		
	&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The above uses the default "Ansi" encoding, which we have
	conveniently mapped in Mono to do a conversion from Unicode to
	utf-8 (Gtk+ uses utf-8 as input).  But this is not entirely
	correct.  The trouble is that to be &lt;i&gt;entirely&lt;/i&gt; correct we
	will have to generate code like this:

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre id="code"&gt;
[DllImport("libgtk-win32-2.0-0.dll")]
static extern void gtk_label_set_text(IntPtr raw, IntPtr str);

public string Text { 
	set {
		// Marshaller is a helper class that every developer
		// has to roll on its own.
                IntPtr raw_str = Marshaller.ConvertToUTF8 (value);
		gtk_label_set_text(Handle, raw_str);
		Marshaller.PtrToStringGFree (raw_str);
	}
}		
	&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;This is not a problem for Gtk# which is generating the
	bindings for us, just a bit more of annoyance, but it is a
	problem for newcomers to .NET who will find the above just too
	complicated for average use.  Not only that, but the other
	problem is that most of the time the app &lt;i&gt;appears&lt;/i&gt; to
	work.  It is only under stress conditions found during
	deployment (or testing if you are lucky) that the developer
	will be bit by this missing functionality. &lt;/p&gt; 
	
	&lt;p&gt;We identified a couple of unused bits on the encoding for
	this attribute in the ECMA spec, and suggested that they get
	used for the most populate encodings (utf-8 and ucs-2 I
	believe), but we were turned down by Microsoft.  The current
	position is to use a platform specific attribute to encode
	this.  This has problems, because we can not be compatible
	with .NET unless we all adopt the same scheme.  The other
	problem is that by using a real custom attribute to do this,
	as opposed to a synthesized one (the attribute being turned
	into a bit value) is that we will loose performance.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Anyways, too bad that Microsoft is not interested in fixing
	this platform usability issue, specially since they have been
	focusing on fixing things that would force programmers to
	write more code.  This seems like one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F13%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F13%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Sep 2003: Fixed my compiler so it could compile another compiler which can compile itself.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        I fixed a few bugs in ilasm today and got it to the point that
        Oberon could assemble and display its usage text. Feeling
        brave I tried a hello world.
        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;img src="../images/Screenshot-Oberon.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;It worked!!! Here is a quick rundown of what you just
        looked at:
        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The Oberon compiler is assembled by ilasm&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The newly created Oberon compiler compiles a hello
        world&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Oberon launches ilasm to assemble the hello world (1970s
        style of writing a compiler)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The compiled and assembled hello world is run&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The Active Oberon for .net compiler is self hosting on
        Mono. This means that the compiler can compile itself. This is
        possible because the Oberon compiler actually just creates
        ilasm code files and then uses the ilasm assembler to convert
        these code files into a binary application or library. So I
        can now compile the Oberon compiler with the Oberon compiler,
        then take that newly compiled compiler and compile the Oberon
        compiler, .....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I wrote this really small and really pointless program in
        ilasm today. Thought I would post it because lots of people
        ask me what ilasm looks like.
        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;div style="margin-left: 1cm; margin-right:1cm;
             background: #c0d0ff; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;
             padding: 1px; border-style: solid; border-width: 1px;"&gt;
             &lt;pre&gt;
.assembly extern mscorlib { }
.assembly 'test-a.exe' { }
&lt;p&gt;
.class public T {
&lt;p&gt;
        .method public static void Main ()
        {        
                .entrypoint
                .locals init (class [mscorlib]System.IO.StreamWriter)
&lt;p&gt;
                ldstr "test"
                newobj void [mscorlib]System.IO.StreamWriter::.ctor (string)
                stloc.0
&lt;p&gt;
                ldloc.0
                ldstr "TEST"
                callvirt void [mscorlib]System.IO.StreamWriter::WriteLine (string)
&lt;p&gt;
                ldloc.0
                callvirt void [mscorlib]System.IO.StreamWriter::Close ()
&lt;p&gt;
                ret
        }
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This is a really simple app that just creates a file named
        'test' and writes the word 'TEST' to it. It then closes the
        file. This should be wrapped in a try/catch/finally block but
        I didnt feel like blowing anyones mind tonight. We will do
        that tommorow ;-).
        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F13%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F13%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Sep 2003: Mono, .NET and Java</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft recently sponsored a research to compare the
	development costs of using .NET and J2EE to build enterprise
	applications.  The story is &lt;a
	href="http://story.news.yahoo.com/news?tmpl=story&amp;cid=581&amp;ncid=581&amp;e=5&amp;u=/nm/20030909/tc_nm/tech_microsoft_linux_dc"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The results are not surprising to me.  The study claims
	that .NET is on aveage 28% cheaper than developing with
	J2EE-based frameworks.  Both J2EE and Swing have been
	over-engineered and over-designed.  It is probably a very
	solid design, but has abused the model-view-controller
	architecture.  If not kept under adult supervision architects
	designing MVC platforms make the development of average
	applications cumbersome.&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;The results are exactly along the lines of the input we
	received in March 2003 when we did the &lt;a
	href="http://www.go-mono.com/index.html#Mar25th:SecondMonoSurvey"&gt;Second
	Mono Survey&lt;/a&gt;.  Our Survey focused on ASP.NET as a
	technology for developing web-based applications, and the
	people we had a chance to interview gave us that same message:
	ASP.NET saves them on average 20% of their development
	time.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The research study we did shed some light into the debate.
	The application serving market can be divided in three
	groups:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;table border=1 cellpadding=3&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;Market&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;Development&lt;br&gt;Price Range (dollars)&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;Technologies&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;State&lt;/td&gt;
	   &lt;/tr&gt;
	   &lt;tr&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;Entry level&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;0-200,000&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;Php, Python, Zope, Perl, home-grown, cgi-bin, 
	     asp, aps.net, jsp, j2ee&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;Plenty of offerings, no dominant player.&lt;br&gt;
	   &lt;/tr&gt;
	   &lt;tr&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;Mid level&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;200,000 to 5,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;J2EE, ASP.NET&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;J2EE had an early start, but ASP.NET is taking over.&lt;br&gt;
	     These are multi-developer projects of six to twelve
	     months.  This market is very sensitive to development
	     times, and a 20% to 28% increase in productivity makes
	     ASP.NET solutions more competitive price-wise and more
	     profitable.   The Windows-only nature of ASP.NET its the
	     only thing stopping its mass adoption.
	   &lt;/tr&gt;
	   &lt;tr&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;High level&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;5,000,000+&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;J2EE and ASP.NET&lt;/td&gt;
	     &lt;td&gt;J2EE is considered the standard to use.  These projects
	     require hardware mobility and are large
	     organizational projects.  The availability of many J2EE
	     providers is considered a big plus.&lt;br&gt;
	     The lack of third-party providers for ASP.NET slows down
	     its adoption in this market.
	   &lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Mono is by no means ready to be an ASP.NET provider on the
	high-level application server market today, but the mid-market
	is the sweet spot for Mono and will help drive the adoption of
	ASP.NET.  This is very compelling, because developers can use
	the state-of-the-art Visual Studio to create their
	applications (cutting costs there), and deploy on Linux
	(cutting costs on the server side).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Plugins in Mono&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Nat asked me to write a small document for people who are
	interesting in creating applications with plugins.  The
	following is the smallest setup I could think of (this is the
	same model I used on the &lt;a
	href="http://www.nat.org/dashboard/"&gt;Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;).
	
&lt;h3&gt;Plugins in Mono: (&lt;a href="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel//texts/cli-plugins.html"&gt;Article Permalink&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The Common Language Infrastructure has various mechanisms
	that developers can use to extend their applications with
	plugins.  This document describes the facilities available and
	some possible implementation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Plugins are dynamically loaded modules that extend the
	functionality of an application.  Plugins can be used to
	enable developers to extend an application after it has
	shipped, and also as a modularization technique.  Applications
	like the GIMP use a plugin architecture to implement
	transformation and file formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;CLI Foundations&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;When a program or a library are compiled into assemblies
	(the binary file format used by the CLI)the information about
	the available classes, methods, variables, names, parameters
	are stored into the resulting .exe or .dll.  This information
	can be later retrieved through the Reflection API.

	&lt;p&gt;Technically, the only difference between a .exe and a .dll in
	the CLI world is that executable files contain an entry point,
	and libraries do not.&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;For example, the following program will list all of the
	types available in an assembly.  Both a .exe or a .dll will
	work:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #ddddff; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
using System;
using System.Reflection;

class ListTypes {
	static void Main (string [] args)
	{
		foreach (string file in args){
			Assembly a = Assembly.LoadFrom (file);

			Type [] types = a.GetTypes ();

			Console.WriteLine ("Assembly: " + file);
			foreach (Type t in types)
				Console.WriteLine ("   Type: " + t.Name);
		}
	}
}&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Compile and run: &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #000000; color: #777777; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
$ mcs query.cs
Compilation succeeded
$ mono query.exe demo.exe
Assembly: query.exe
   Type: Class1
$ _&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Once an assembly is loaded, it is also possible to extract
	the available methods or dynamically invoke methods in the
	recently loaded assembly.  For example, the following program
	will invoke the method "Boot" on any types passed on the
	command line.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #ddddff; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
using System;
using System.Reflection;

class ListTypes {
	static void Main (string [] args)
	{
		foreach (string file in args){
			Assembly a = Assembly.LoadFrom (file);

			Type [] types = a.GetTypes ();

			Console.WriteLine ("Assembly: " + file);
			foreach (Type t in types){
				MethodInfo boot = t.GetMethod ("Boot");
				if (boot == null)
					continue;

				if (!boot.IsStatic)
					continue;
					
				boot.Invoke (null, new Type [0]);
			}
		}
	}
}&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;We are using the Type's GetMethod to fetch the public
	method named "Boot".   If we find such a method, we invoke
	it.  In this particular example, we want to invoke static
	methods, so we test for this and we also pass `null' as the
	first argument to Invoke.&lt;/p

	&lt;p&gt;The following sample program can be used to test our new
	loader:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #ddddff; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
using System;
	
public class Demo {
	public static void Boot ()
	{
		Console.WriteLine ("Demo.Boot invoked");
	}
}&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;We compile and run:&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #000000; color: #777777; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
$ mcs loader.cs
Compilation succeeded
$ mcs -target:library demo.cs
Compilation succeeded
$ mono loader.exe demo.dll
Assembly: demo.dll
Demo.Boot invoked
$ _&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Access to the Main Application&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to load code dynamically, but a
	plugin-system often will need to access the internal data
	structures and methods to carry out a more interesting job.
	Our plugins can invoke easily any methods that is available to
	thme at compilation time.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The following sample program shows a tiny spreadsheet
	application which provides support for invoking plugins. 
	
	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #ddddff; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
using System;
using System.Reflection;

public class Spreadsheet {
	string [,] cells = new string [10, 10];

	public string this [int col, int row] {
		get {
			return cells [col, row];
		}

		set {
			cells [col,row] = value;
		}
	}
}

public class Driver {
	static public Spreadsheet sheet = new Spreadsheet ();
	
	static void Main ()
	{
		string cmd, r;

		do {
			Console.Write ("cmd&gt; ");
			cmd = Console.ReadLine ();

			string [] args = cmd.Split (new char [] {' '});
			
			switch (args [0]){
			case "set": 
				sheet [Byte.Parse (args [1]),
				       Byte.Parse (args [2])] = args [3];
				break;

			case "get":
			        r = sheet [Byte.Parse (args [1]),
				           Byte.Parse (args [2])];
				Console.WriteLine ("value: {0}", r);
				break;

			case "plugin":
				InvokePlugin (args [1]);
				break;
			}
		} while (cmd != "quit");
	}

	static void InvokePlugin (string plugin)
	{
		Assembly a = Assembly.LoadFrom (plugin);

		foreach (Type t in a.GetTypes ()){
			MethodInfo method = t.GetMethod ("SheetPlugin");

			if (method != null &amp;&amp; method.IsStatic){
				method.Invoke (null, new Type [0]);
				break;
			}
		}
	}
}&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Compile the above like this:&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #000000; color: #777777; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
$ mcs sheet.cs
Compilation succeeded
$ _&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Here is the `export.cs' program that we will compile as a
	plugin:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #ddddff; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
using System;
	
public class DumpSheet {
	public static void SheetPlugin ()
	{
		for (int r = 0; r &lt; 10; r++){
			for (int c = 0; c &lt; 10; c++)
				Console.Write ("{0}, ", Driver.sheet [r, c]);
			Console.WriteLine ();
		}
	}
}&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Notice that this plugin needs to access the sheet object in
	the Driver class from the main program.  We will compile this
	as a library which &lt;b&gt;references&lt;/b&gt; the main application.
	This effectively treats the main application as a library
	consumed by the plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #000000; color: #777777; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
$ mcs export.cs -r:sheet.exe -target:library
Compilation succeeded
$ _&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;A sample session looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre style="border-style: solid; background: #000000; color: #777777; border-width: 1px; padding: 2pt;"&gt;
$ mono sheet.exe
cmd&gt; set 0 0 hello
cmd&gt; set 0 1 world
cmd&gt; set 8 8 Eight
cmd&gt; plugin export.dll
hello, world, , , , , , , , , 
, , , , , , , , , , 
, , , , , , , , , , 
, , , , , , , , , , 
 , , , , , , , , , 
, , , , , , , , , , 
, , , , , , , , , , 
, , , , , , , , , , 
, , , , , , , , Eight, , 
, , , , , , , , , , 
cmd&gt; _&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Details&lt;/h3&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of other scenarios and ways of structuring
	your program to have a plugin system.  Currently part of the
	contract used in this document was to use the public classes,
	methods and fields exposed by the host application.  A common
	pattern used in plugin systems is to provide a class method to
	register objects and handlers with the host application.&lt;/p&gt;

	

&lt;h3&gt;Gnome 2.4 is out&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The anticipated release of Gnome 2.4 is &lt;a
	href="http://www.gnome.org/start/2.4/"&gt;out now&lt;/a&gt;.  It
	includes a list of &lt;a
	href="http://www.gnome.org/start/2.4/notes/rnwhy.html"&gt;Why
	use Gnome?&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Ars Technica has a &lt;a
	href="http://arstechnica.com/reviews/003/software/gnome-2.4/gnome2.4-1.html"&gt;pretty
	good review.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F12%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F12%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Sep 2003: Nothing is official until you see it on IRC</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt; I will be joining the Novell Ximian Services business
         unit of Novell in October. Needless to say, I am jack's total
         excitment. I would write more about this but I have lots of
         hacking to do ;-).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
         &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;Trying to get &lt;a
         href="http://www.oberon.ethz.ch/lightning/"&gt;Active Oberon for
         .net&lt;/a&gt; working on Mono this weekend. This a great test for
         ilasm.
         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
         &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;
         I am now on &lt;a
         href="http://www.advogato.org/person/jackson/"&gt;Advogato&lt;/a&gt;.
         Should be a humbling experience ;-).
         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
         
         
&lt;p&gt;
         
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F12%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F12%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Sep 2003: Barcelona</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plenty of us the Mono developers and Linux developer got
	together during the Brainshare event in Barcelona.  Lluis (the
	man behind the implementation of Mono's Remoting and Mono's
	WebServices support) lives in Barcelona, and Gonzalo (Mono's
	ASP.NET developer) was coming back from vacation from
	Istambul.  It was the perfect chance to discuss Mono. &lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Juantoms (&lt;a
	href="http://www.hispalinux.es"&gt;HispaLinux's&lt;/a&gt; president)
	joined us on Monday night, and Man, Andreu and Osorio showed
	up on Tuesday for a few hours for dinner.  We had a great time
	with both our new co-workers are Novell and the Spanish Linux
	crowd in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Jordi Mas who has been working on Abiword and on the
	catalonian support for various free software projects is
	developing an interest for Mono.  He has plenty of Win32
	experience, and he is interested in helping us move Mono's
	Windows.Forms support forward.  He advocates following a
	single path: Wine-based Windows.Forms and customizations to
	Wine to make it track the Gtk+ theme and dropping our support
	for the Gtk+ based toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Spent a fair amount of time with &lt;a
	href="http://www.nat.org"&gt;Nat&lt;/a&gt;: mostly at night when
	tracking the best restaurants that served jamn and the bars
	afterwards.  Nat had a little accident with his new cell
	phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Novell&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of joining Novell for us was that our
	products have a much bigger audience now.  This is due to the
	fantastic channel that Novell has with enterprises.  During
	the conference we met many sales and solution engineers of
	Novell, many of them already with contacts of people
	interested in Linux-based solutions (both the Novell Linux
	software stack for servers as well as the desktop side).&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Plenty of people at the confere are considering Linux on
	the desktop, a recurrent topic with people we met on the
	hallways was large scale enterprise deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;XD2 has the right mix of components to make the Linux
	Desktop on enterprises a reality:

	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;GNOME 2.4 has been making tremendous progress in
		terms of accessibility, ease-of-use, simplicity, API
		stability and the &lt;a
		href="http://foundation.gnome.org"&gt;Gnome
		Foundation&lt;/a&gt; who has helped focus the development on
		these important projects. 

		&lt;li&gt;OpenOffice is maturing, and we are commited to
		keep improving the common code base on which
		OpenOffice is built to help people migrate and reduce
		their costs of deployment. 
		
		&lt;li&gt;Mozilla: a fantastic standards compliant browser.
		My favorite feature today: tabbed browsing, the
		smartbar plugin.

		&lt;li&gt;Red Carpet: A recurrent theme we hear about people
		doing large desktop deployments is that they need a
		way of managing these machines.  Red Carpet does a lot
		today, and the management roadmap is at the center of
		the development effort right now.

		&lt;li&gt;Evolution: Mail, calendar and addressbook, with
		groupware collaboration.
	&lt;/ul&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Nat did one of the most amazing presentations I have ever
	seen on why the above software stack is the right one for
	Linux on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;We are collaborating with other teams inside Novell to
	support the Novell software stack: Groupwise, i-Folder,
	e-Directory and Liberty Aliance authentication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;More Gnome Deployments&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;In Andaluca, 20,000 Gnome desktops were just &lt;a
	href="http://www.20minutos.es/sevilla/?noti=66321"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt;.
	I have to take a trip there to witness this again.  20,000
	Gnome-based machines on 1,800 schools in Andalucia.  I
	&lt;i&gt;have&lt;/i&gt; to go see this.  Congrats Gnome folks!

	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.telecentros.sp.gov.br"&gt;Telecentros
	experience&lt;/a&gt; in Sao Paolo was very interesting, because the
	site I went to was one of the centros equipped with
	accessibility hardware.
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F11%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F11%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Sep 2003: One more form!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt; Cats out of the bag! Tommorow I will explain. Tonight I am
     jacks tedious paper work. One more form. So instead of
     filling out that last form I am blogging ;-).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;
     Thinking about doing something impractical: (not for a few
     more months though)
     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;div style="margin-left: 1cm; margin-right:1cm;
             background: #c0d0ff; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;
             padding: 1px; border-style: solid; border-width: 1px;"&gt;
     &lt;blockquote&gt;
      Classic &amp; Collectibles  (08/28/03)
      '66 IMPALA "SS" STYLE rally whls, lthr buckets, nice looking cruiser.
     &lt;/blockquote&gt;
     &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;Why have a reliable car when you could have an un-reliable but
     cool car? I am going to hold out for a convertible though. Roxy
     would love it and I bet they get real cheap during the winters in
     BC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F11%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F11%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Sep 2003: Today I didnt even have to use my AK (&lt;a href="#ak_discl"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
       I am still undecided about &lt;a
       href="http://www.famousplayers.com/movies/movie_information.asp?movie=97B1C6E6-D1F2-441A-BFC8-3F1BD1CCCA92"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
       I am not sure if it is super awesome or super lame. Either way
       I am going ;-). Tommorow I am going to help fund the &lt;a
       href="http://www.foxnews.com/story/0,2933,96797,00.html"&gt;war on
       12 year old girls&lt;/a&gt; by purchasing Bowie's new album.
       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
       I have a feeling that the link in todays title bar is going to
       break the RSS.....lets see what happens.
       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
       &lt;a name="ak_discl"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt;For those of you over 30 I do
       not actually own an AK this is a reference to an Ice Cube song about
       having a good day.
       &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F10%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F10%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Sep 2003: New domain name</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt; This site has been moved to &lt;a
     href="http://www.jacksonh.net"&gt;jacksonh.net&lt;/a&gt;. So update your
     bookmarks, update your RSS feeds, and update your links (I know
     there are two). I will make the switch in my rss files tonight.
     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt; Hockey tonight. Tommorow I will have a post something like
     this:
     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
        Played hockey last night for the first time this
        season. Couldn't control my rebounds at all. I am really sore
        this morning.
        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
             
     
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F09%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F09%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Sep 2003: Wet paws</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;
     Roxy just passed up walking in the park because she didn't want
     to get her paws wet. Crazy dog.
     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;
     Read &lt;a
     href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/comment/story/0,3604,1036571,00.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.
     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;
     Note to everyone. Please start calling BenM b-diddy.
     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;
     ilasm has a couple of cool exception handling mechanisms that C#
     does not (sorry miguel ;-)). The first neato exception handling
     mechanism is the filter block. Filter blocks allow you to perform
     some logic and decide whether or not to enter a handler
     block. Here is some pseudo code:
     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;div style="margin-left: 1cm; margin-right:1cm;
             background: #c0d0ff; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;
             padding: 1px; border-style: solid; border-width: 1px;"&gt;
     &lt;pre&gt;
     try {
         exception thrown
     } filter {
         decide whether or not we want to handle this exception
     } {
         block that handles the exception
     }
     &lt;/pre&gt;
     &lt;/div&gt;
     
     &lt;p&gt;
     The second and maybe even cooler exception handling mechanism is
     the fault block. A fault block is like a finally block except it
     only gets called if an exception is thrown in the gaurded
     block. Here is a some pseudo code:
     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;div style="margin-left: 1cm; margin-right:1cm;
             background: #c0d0ff; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px;
             padding: 1px; border-style: solid; border-width: 1px;"&gt;
     &lt;pre&gt;
             try {
                exception thrown sometimes
             } fault {
                this code is executed whenever an exception is thrown
             }
     &lt;/pre&gt;  
     &lt;/div&gt;     
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F08%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F08%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Sep 2003: Barcelona</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I arrived to Barcelona for the Novell &lt;a
	href="http://www.novell.com/brainshare/europe/"&gt;Brainshare&lt;/a&gt;
	event.  

	&lt;p&gt;Got together with Chema, Lluis and Nat.  Went relatively
	early back to the hotel, and discovered that we had wireless
	access, so we hung around until 4am.  Nat's humor quality is
	directly proportional to how long he has gone without
	sleeping. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Monodoc editing&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;In our effort to improve the documentation in Mono we have
	been working on a GUI tool to browse all kinds of
	documentation (Monodoc), but we need more people documenting
	our APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;To address this problem, we are making it &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt;
	simple for people to contribute documentation: we have made
	our documentation editable.  When you are viewing a stub, you
	have the choice to edit it; For example:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;div style="margin-left: 1cm; margin-right:1cm; background: #c0d0ff; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0px; padding: 1px; border-style: solid; border-width: 1px;"&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Summary&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; To be added &lt;a
	href=""&gt;[Edit]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
	       
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I recently added a preview viewer for it, for example here
	we are editing some documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;img src="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/images/Screenshot-LiveEdit.png"&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;All those changes are saved into a changeset, that the
	contributor can submit when he is ready.   We will submit
	those using Mono's web services infrastructure.  When the
	changes are reviewed and approved, we commit those to CVS, and
	they appear on the next release of the code.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;This same infrastructure will help for our collaborative
	annotations for the documentation.  This is important to have
	people share their personal experiences and samples for any
	given API.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F07%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F07%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Sep 2003: Interesting night</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
             &lt;p&gt;
             Went to a friends farewell-to-my-house party last
             night. Made some new interesting and intriguing
             friends. Should have brought Camera.
             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
             &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
             &lt;p&gt;
             Malloc and Calloc have arrived. Roxy really likes the
             smell of their food.
             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
             &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
             &lt;p&gt;
             Just made some damn good chicken...yum. The best part is
             that I washed the dishes while it was cooking so there is
             no post dinner mess. Pure genius. Now its time to clear
             out the backlog of stuff I need to do on my home
             computers. Here is a quick list:
             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
             &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Get wireless card startup script working with
                ifup/ifdown&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Remove the 100 lines of debugging info that my
                wireless card drivers spews every time I boot&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Script for uploading my blog files&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;In emacs I want meta-x lb to create and upload my
                blog&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Setup some NFS&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Take NAT off my desktop (the router will handle
                this now)&lt;/li&gt;
             &lt;/ul&gt;   
             
&lt;p&gt;
             
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F07%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F07%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Sep 2003: Mexico it is!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Well I went back and forth and back and forth on this
        one. Bottom line is Mexico City has all sorts of things I want
        to see and people I want to meet. The size of the city
        fascinates me, and I cant wait to see it. I cant wait to see
        some ruins, meet jscript hacker Cesar face to face , see
        Miguel on his home turf, and hopefully visit with some other
        Mono hackers. I have 6 days to decide on a date for visiting
        Mexico City.
        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Meanwhile north of the 49th parallel I have moved back into my
        apartment. I am suffering from lack of stuff
        syndrome that will clear up over the next few months. I setup
        my wireless access point and can sit out on the couch with
        Roxy and hack away.
        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Tommorow Roxy and I will recruit two new members into our
        gang. I have already decided on names for the new
        recruits. Malloc and Calloc will become the newest additions
        to the posie. They will be gold fish, or some other type of
        fish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; What I really like about blogs is that people write about
        other peoples &lt;a
        href="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F05%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00"&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F06%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#09%2F06%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Sep 2003: If you read one web page this month</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What I really like about blogs is that sometimes people sit
	down, and write little essays reflecting on their experience.
	My personal choice is from the craftsmen: because they tell
	you tales and lesson from the trenches.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I can not make justice to the beauty of Eric's latest
	entry: &lt;a
	href="http://software.ericsink.com/20030903.html"&gt;F5&lt;/a&gt;.


	
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F05%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F05%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Sep 2003: The history of SWT and Swing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While doing my daily reading of the SWT-port-to-C# reading
	this morning, found this &lt;a
	href="http://www.mail-archive.com/jug-discussion@tucson-jug.org/msg00355.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;
	that describes the torrid story of Swing and SWT.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; That document contains various errors on the
	side of the origins of Swing.  For more details see this &lt;a
	href="http://www.javalobby.com/threadMode2.jsp?forum=61&amp;thread=7034&amp;start=-1"&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Amy describes her experiences with the iPod and a native
	user interface &lt;a
	href="http://weblogs.java.net/pub/wlg/244"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Very
	good point about using native interfaces.  Firebird already
	has a couple of XUL-based clients that let the user browse
	Amazon more comfortably than using the regular Web interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Al Franken's book&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I have been reading Al Franken's &lt;a
	href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0525947647/qid=1062691957/sr=8-1/ref=sr_8_1/103-9624440-8714218?v=glance&amp;s=books&amp;n=507846"&gt;Lies&lt;/a&gt;
	book.  It has been entertaining for the past couple of days,
	but it turned out &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; interesting on the
	chapter on the Clinton efforts on the war against terror and
	how the Bush administration dropped the ball on that (chapter
	15, but it shines on chapter 16).&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I tried writting a summary, but its impossible to make
	justice to those two chapters.  It is particularly
	interesting, because Franken got a team of Harvard graduates
	from the Kennedy school to fact-check everything he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Anyways: mandatory reading if you stop by a book store.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Cant wait&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;To see The Band on the Runtime &lt;a
	href="http://www.gotdotnet.com/team/dbox/default.aspx?key=2003-09-04T07:00:42Z"&gt;perform&lt;/a&gt;

	
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F04%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F04%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Sep 2003: My new T40 and Linux.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am using a new IBM T40 now as my main computer.  I was
	about to go for the X31 which is lighter and smaller, but I
	have gotten used to the large resolution from my old T30.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a
	href="http://primates.ximian.com/~notzed/diary.html"&gt;Michael
	Zucchi&lt;/a&gt; provided me with a few links to people running
	Linux on the T40.  Most hardware is supported on the T40, but
	the speed of the hard drive left much to be desired.  The new
	T40 felt like it could not handle the load the T30 did.  Any
	IO would make the system very slow.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;After dropping by the #kernel channel on LinuxNet, I was
	told to upgrade my Kernel to the latest RH update.  So far the
	speed of my hard drive went from 2.5 MB/second to 25
	Mb/second.  An e-mail expunge that used to take about two
	minutes seconds, now takes 13 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F03%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F03%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Sep 2003: The PDC</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am going to the PDC, hoping to listen to Don's &lt;a
	href="http://www.gotdotnet.com/team/dbox/default.aspx?key=2003-09-02T06:22:36Z"&gt;new
	single&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Gonzalo and Lluis from the Mono team are coming as
	well.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Also found the &lt;a
	href="http://pdcbloggers.net/Default.aspx"&gt;PDC Bloggers&lt;/a&gt; site.
	

&lt;h3&gt;Moving day&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;A completely unproductive day.  I just moved into my new
	apartment, where I will be &lt;a
	href="http://www.nat.org"&gt;Nat's&lt;/a&gt; neighbor.

	&lt;p&gt;Verizon cancelled my DSL during the move, and am using a
	kind soul's wireless access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F02%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#09%2F02%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Aug 2003: The Big Apple</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;
     Five star suggested a combo of NY and Boston for my upcoming
     trip. He is old and wise and I agree with him. I am worried about
     the cost of visiting NY. It will mean sacrificing my new TV and
     iPod fund.
     &lt;/p&gt;
     
     &lt;p&gt;
     I really want to get an iPod but am a little worried
     about Linux support. If anyone reading this is using an iPod with
     Linux could you send me a &lt;a
     href="mailto:jackson@latitudegeo.com"&gt;message&lt;/a&gt;? I would like
     to get a mac but Linux is too important to me, and x86 has been
     kind to me for many years.
     &lt;/p&gt;
     
     &lt;p&gt;
     I am looking forward to moving back into my apartment. Still dont
     know when that will be. I feel like I am in &lt;a
     href="http://www.4degreez.com/misc/dante-inferno-information.html#1"&gt;limbo&lt;/a&gt;
     right now but Homer and Socrates and all the pagans aren't around. I am going to
     have a pretty empty place so maybe I will succum to the dreaded
     &lt;a
     href="http://www.antiessays.com/show.php?cat=arts&amp;eid=2113"&gt;IKEA
     nesting instinct&lt;/a&gt;. 
     &lt;/p&gt;
     
     &lt;p&gt;
     Here is a quick rundown of the last few years of my relationship life in
     internet lingo:  BF -&gt; FH -&gt; DH -&gt; STBX. No I am not the store
     byte indexed instruction ;-).
     &lt;/p&gt;
     
     &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;     
     This weekend I am going to finally get the error reporting fixed
     in ilasm. This will make it allot more fun to write programs
     with. So maybe I will write some more tests too :-).
     &lt;/p&gt;
     
&lt;p&gt;
     
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F31%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F31%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Aug 2003: Congrats Leah!!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
          Leah got a job at what looks like a really cool design firm today.
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F29%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F29%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Aug 2003: The largest Gnome deployment: The Sao Paulo Telecentros</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sao Paulo &lt;a
	href="http://www.telecentros.sp.gov.br."&gt;Telecentros&lt;/a&gt;
	provide service to 150,000 users.   Each Telecentro is running
	a small cluster of computers: a high-end server and 20
	diskless workstations (Pentium class machines).

	&lt;p&gt;The diskless Linux workstations are hooked up to the server
	with a 100mb network, and each workstation boots in 20 to 30
	seconds (this is from memory).  Very fast.  All applications
	run on a pretty big server, and OpenOffice is pre-loaded, so
	it starts in no time.&lt;/P&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Each Telecentro offers service to about 3,000 users;
	People schedule time on the workstations in slots of half an
	hour or an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;They have written lots of tutorials in Portuguese in each
	of the Telecentros and cover the basics: the Gnome desktop,
	Star Writer, Star Calc, Galeon and Gnome Paint.

	&lt;p&gt;Today there are &lt;a
	href="http://www.telecentros.sp.gov.br/mapa.php"&gt;72
	telecentros&lt;/a&gt; open for a total of 107 planned.  The cost of
	setting up a telecentro is 10,000 dollars.

	&lt;p&gt;During my visit to the Telecentro's headquarters, I heard a
	few new arguments I had not heard before about the advantages
	of free software:

	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Cost-wise: They were able to deploy 80
		tele-centros instead of 20.

		&lt;li&gt;The government initiative of
		&lt;i&gt;Digital-inclusion&lt;/i&gt; means that users that use the
		software setups today can take the software home and
		replicate *the exact* functionality.

		&lt;li&gt;Number of applications: There are 1,700 software
		programs available as part of the Debian Linux
		distribution which are both free and legal for the
		users to copy.
	&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F29%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F29%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Aug 2003: Generics, generics</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Martin reports:
	&lt;tt&gt;
* baulig just compiled his first "Hello Generic World" :-)
	&lt;/tt&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The Mono C# compiler today compiled it first generics
	program (see the various generic tests on CVS).  It is still
	lacking support for method overloading.  All the goodies are
	in mcs/gmcs (the special tree for our generics compiler).&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Paolo had previously added the Generics support to our
	class libraries (System.Reflection and System.Reflection.Emit)
	and added the code to JIT generics code.  This was helped
	enormously by Jackson's earlier work on the IL Assembler which
	was already generics aware.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;In .NET 2.0, Generics are part of the instruction set,
	and the metadata in an executable.   Some of the advantages of
	this approach vs the C++ mechanism of having the templates
	defines in .h files is that we keep getting the performance
	increase from having the generics information "pre-compiled".
	Those of us with a Turbo Pascal background, cant help but
	think `These are like the Turbo Pascal Units (TPUs): they were
	just so much better than C libraries and header files'.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Its surprising how a good idea like TPUs did not take over
	the industry, and instead the C libraries and headers was kept
	on use for so long.   GC was also around a long time ago, and
	it is surprising that today C and C++ are still the standard
	for software production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Monodoc progres&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Even more progress on Monodoc.  Ben now got an `error
	messages provider', and we have included all the errors mcs
	produces (all 311 of them) with sample files in the
	documentation.  Mandatory &lt;a
	href="http://users.hawken.edu/05mauben/Screenshot-mdoc-error.png"&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F28%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F28%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Aug 2003: Travel suggestions</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        I have until Sept. 14th to book a flight to anywhere within
        700 dollars of Victoria. So I am looking for
        &lt;a
        href="mailto:jackson@latitudegeo.com"&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt;. Anyone
        know of anything cool I should try to visit in a few months?
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        Here is a list of places I am thinking about, in a random
        order ;-).
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Boston&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Orlando&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Mexico City&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F28%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F28%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Aug 2003: Time to tell the world</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
      A few people already know this, but not everybody that
      should. I really don't feel like talking about this much so I am
      just going to blog it, because I know everyone reads my blog
      ;-).
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      Leah and I are permanently separated. We are not taking some
      time apart, or 'just dating'. This is pretty final. I'm not
      going to go into the details of why because I really don't fully
      understand. Everyone has questions for me now about my life. I
      really don't have that many answers and I find trying to answer
      the questions I do not have answers for very frustrating. So I
      will give the world the answers I have.
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Are you going to move from Victoria? &lt;b&gt;No&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Who is going to take care of Roxy? &lt;b&gt;Leah is taking care
        of Roxy right now. Once she moves out I will take care of her
        until Leah has more permanent plans.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Where are you staying? &lt;b&gt;At my dads&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;How long are you staying there? &lt;b&gt;Until Leah finds a
        job/apartment hopefully within the month.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Are you still going to Mexico? &lt;b&gt;No&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      These are the only answers I have right now, as things become
      less blurry I will post more.
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      I prefer to think of this as a 'reclassification of relationship
      status' we have changed from being husband and wife to friend
      and friend. I hope that we can remain as good friends. 
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
      
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F27%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F27%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Aug 2003: Mono Developments</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zoltan Varga has removed the big locks we had on the Mono
	runtime, and has replaced them with fine-grained locks using a
	lattice to describe the order in which the locks are to be
	obtained to avoid dead-lock situations.   This was part of the
	thread safety audit on the Mono runtime engine.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="www.atoker.com"&gt;Alp&lt;/a&gt; improved the UI of
	Monodoc, so it now looks a lot prettier:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;img
	src="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/images/monodoc-2.png"&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Other changes in Monodoc during the past week include the
	display of extra information for matches, in this case, I
	selected the "ToString" method from the incremental search
	window, and a list of matches is displayed:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;img
	src="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/images/monodoc-matches.png"&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Johannes today contributed a patch to Mono's Windows.Forms
	that makes it track the Gtk theme colors; His new patch will
	also pick the default font settings.  You can see it &lt;a
	href="http://www.sport-huettn.de/jroith/swfsample.png"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Gonzalo in the meantime made me very happy with the changes
	to XSP (our ASP.NET server) that allow for multiple
	applications to be hosted on a single server.  This finally
	will let me run all my web apps and web services under
	Apache.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The SharpWT team has a full C#-based version of SWT ready
	to run, and they have made tremendous progress on the toolkit
	in the last two weeks (working both on Windows and on
	Gtk+).&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The Mono Brazil site is &lt;a
	href="http://monobrasil.redesolbrasil.org/twiki/bin/view/Main/MonoBrasil"&gt;Up&lt;/a&gt;.
	It is TWiki based, but the content is there now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hip stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Today's hip thing is of course the text-mode &lt;a
	href="http://zemljanka.sourceforge.net/cursed/"&gt;Gtk+&lt;/a&gt;.  I
	love this hack, and am puzzled by their effort to build a
	Midnight Commander-like program using it, but the &lt;a
	href="http://zemljanka.sourceforge.net/"&gt;pages&lt;/a&gt; are in
	Czech.

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.gotdotnet.com/cbrumme/"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt;
	Brumme's &lt;a
	href="http://blogs.gotdotnet.com/cbrumme/PermaLink.aspx/dac5ba4a-f0c8-42bb-a5cf-097efb25d1a9"&gt;last
	post&lt;/a&gt; on his blog is also fascinating: many internal
	details about the CLR are exposed, but also, I am still quite
	surprised by the layering done by NT on their low-level
	loading interfaces, it seems too complicated when you contrast
	it with ELF file loading (seems to me like a backwards
	compatibility feature).  Mono happily can avoid a lot of this,
	but for a price: they are today executing C++ code out of the
	box, we cant yet.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Michael Meeks is also &lt;a
	href="http://www.gnome.org/~michael/index.html#2003-08-27"&gt;showing
	off&lt;/a&gt; what &lt;i&gt;seems&lt;/i&gt; to the uninformed viewer like a
	Gtk-like layout system for Open Office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Guadec, and Linux at Work?&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;There are various cities in Europe that want to host the
	Guadec, and we can only host it in one place.  I was thinking
	that maybe after Guadec, or before Guadec, the tutorial
	speakers for Guadec could tour Europe for a week or two,
	delivering tutorials on the various subjects: not really a
	tour aimed at Gnome developers, but aimed at users and
	developers interested in using the Gnome platform.  Very much
	like what the Linux at Work folks do.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;That has the advantage of getting Gnome better known in
	various places in Europe, but focusing our Guadec effort in a
	single city.  What do you think?  &lt;a
	href="mailto:miguel@ximian.com"&gt;Mail me&lt;/a&gt; your thoughts.

&lt;h3&gt;Don: what is that cell phone of yours?&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Don is going around with an absolutely hip SmartPhone
	running the .NET Framework, which am in love with.  But after
	using all my internet browsing powers, I have failed to locate
	the model and provider for it.  It seems to be available only
	in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;If you run into Don, get him to mail me the information
	;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sao Paolo&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Maria Laura and myself arrived to Sao Paolo.  Tomorrow we
	will be visiting the Joao at the telecentros in the Favelas
	where they are using Gnome, Debian and Linux to operate those
	centers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F27%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F27%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Aug 2003: </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        OK, PEAPI definatly is not writing Section headers
        correctly. Should be really easy to fix but I don't have my
        book with me (surprise, surprise).
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F25%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F25%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Aug 2003: Mono from Brazil</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;a
	href="http://www.congresso.gov.br/softwarelivre"&gt;free
	software&lt;/a&gt;meeting in Brasilia, we launched the Mono Brazil
	effort: a community of Brazilian hackers is creating a
	Portuguese community around Mono.  This is an important step
	for the local community, just like the creation of &lt;a
	href="http://www.monohispano.org"&gt;Mono Hispano&lt;/a&gt; was.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;In the meantime in Mono-land things keep moving, I logged
	into IRC recently, only to be bombarded with news about the
	progress in Mono-land: Windows.Forms widget rendering was
	re-structured to better match the rendering model.  Plenty of
	bug fixes in this area, so you might want to get your
	mono-wine packages from the Mono site.

	&lt;p&gt;Duncan also contributed our Cairo bindings to
	System.Drawing (we previously were using Xr, and we have
	finally migrated to the new API).   For those who want to use
	Cairo directly, we do provide a nice Cairo binding as well
	without using System.Drawing.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Atsushi Enomoto continues his work on the XML Schema
	validation.  After watching the XML editor demo after &lt;a
	href="http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,3959,1224399,00.asp"&gt;Don's
	presentation&lt;/a&gt;, I am quite interested in seeing more smart
	XML editors based on this code.  Although &lt;a
	href="http://www.conglomerate.org"&gt;Conglomerate&lt;/a&gt; looks a
	lot nicer, it is very fragile (due to its C heritage ;-) and
	whatever is the language use to describe the graphical
	rendering is not simple.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Microsoft instead chose a different approach: instead of
	making a mapping from the XML schema to describe the rendering
	using the 2 or 3 level system used by Conglomerate, they have
	pluggable renderers into Visual Studio.  So it is possible to
	provide custom editors or renderers for SVG files or
	well-known XML configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Lluis has got all the SourceGear regression tests running
	with Mono now, so I am sure Eric will be very pleased to see
	his product running on Linux (and soon on the Mac, as Paolo
	has been busily hacking on it)&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Vladimir has been busily implementing a .NET version of the
	&lt;a href="http://www.zeroc.com"&gt;Internet Communications
	Engine&lt;/a&gt;: the new hip OO-RPC protocol in the world.  Several
	of the people involved with CORBA contributed to the design of
	this vastly simplified and high-performance RPC system.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Gonzalo has got XSP to support multiple-applications.  This
	means one thing: I am migrating my blog finally to ASP.NET,
	running side-by-side with the ASP.NET-based &lt;a
	href="http://mono.ximian.com:8080"&gt;online Mono docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Martin and Zoltan continue their bug hunting on the
	compiler, class libraries and runtime.  Martin's debugger is
	also becoming more and more stable, but he wont get to work on
	it too much, as C# Generics await him ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Yuri Astrakhan discovered &lt;a
	href="http://www.openi18n.org/subgroups/lade/locale/"&gt;Open
	Internationalization&lt;/a&gt; effort to create a data-base of all
	the things localizable/internationalizable that a framework
	needs to provide.  Dick has been working on this based on some
	empty skeletons we created, but having real data files to work
	with will make our effort more interesting&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Piers again impressed everyone with his Javascript skills:
	he implemented a lighter, more portable, less buggy Javascript
	dynamic tree, which can be seen on the &lt;a
	href="http://mono.ximian.com:8080"&gt;mono docs site&lt;/a&gt;.  Ben in
	the meantime helped me fix a few issues in Monodoc, in
	particular now we get a better hint on multiple matches for
	the same entry on the index, and he also implemented &lt;a
	href="http://users.hawken.edu/05mauben/Screenshot-mdoc-overload.png"&gt;method
	grouping&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;h1&gt;Porto Alegre&lt;/h1&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Been spending most of my time visiting friends and family
	of Laura in Porto Alegre.  Also we have visited Marcelo and
	Suzana a few times at their place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F25%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F25%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Aug 2003: Play day for Roxy</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
      Roxy is coming to visit today, I'm going to take her to Gowlland
      Todd park, and down to the beach for some refreshing ocean
      swimming, way better then the swamp stuff she has been swimming
      in lately.
&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F23%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F23%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Aug 2003: Congrats Miguel and Laura!!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
          Good luck Miguel and Laura best wishes for your new future.
&lt;p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
          
          
&lt;p&gt;
          
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F22%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F22%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Aug 2003: Married</title>
      <description>I got married at 5:30pm in Porto Alegre to Maria Laura.  
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F22%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F22%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Aug 2003: OMG it is early</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
     5:59 sitting in McDonalds because I can't get into my office and
     this is the only place in town that is open. Also I am damn
     hungry. I think PEAPI isn't writing section headers properly. 
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;
     
     I guess 3 minutes for a hashbrown means 30. I don't think I could
     eat one right now anyways.
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     A few things I want to do in the next year.
&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Snowboard&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bennerboat.com/" target="_new"&gt;Build
        my own kayak&lt;/a&gt; (yes I know that I can not afford that kit)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Get decent at basketball&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Learn to read Roxy's &lt;a
        href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0806976772/lacetoleather/103-5052997-8327057"&gt;mind-brain function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F21%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F21%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Aug 2003: A fresh new chapter?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        The rules for data are a little hard to figure out from
        looking at the grammar and once again I have forgotten my
        specs. I get the impression that you can not reference data in
        any scope other then the scope you are in. So while you are in
        a type definition you can not reference global data. This is
        not much of a handicap because global data can be mapped to
        global fields that can be referenced from a type definition. I
        know this is exciting info for everyone so I will keep you
        posted.
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        Sitting on the bus feeling very ill tracking down what I think
        might be a really nasty hard to find bug in PEAPI....still
        possible it is in ilasm bug though. Despite being on a wild
        bug hunt, feeling sick, riding on a hot bumpy bus, and all of
        the other negatives in my life I am in a really good mood
        right now. Great news today, check back soon for more info
        :-).
&lt;p&gt;
        
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F20%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F20%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Aug 2003: Flan in the face</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
      About half way through my hour long busride to work. Just
      finished implementing long form overrides in ilasm. If I ever
      meet someone that uses long form overrides in ilasm I would be
      very surprised. Overall ilasm is starting to look pretty good, I
      think I will go on a robustness rampage over the next few days,
      and get all the reporting/error handling implemented. I'v said
      that before though ;-).
&lt;p&gt;
      Sitting on the bus wishing I had my ilasm book with me. I want
      to finish implementing mapped data values but I don't have the
      spec with me. The ILASM book comes with a digital version. I
      should see if I can get that running on GNU/Linux....odds are
      not good. It is microsoft press. I also need to get the ecma
      specs on this machine.
&lt;p&gt;
      
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F19%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F19%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Aug 2003: Sleeping in their shoes</title>
      <description>Sitting on the bus listening to two dudes talking about
          firewalls. Kinda entertaining. Also trying to fix overrides
          in ilasm but I think I broke my runtime last night and I
          don't want to waste the battery power to rebuild right
          now. Still have another hour of bussing it. NOTE TO
          BCTRANSIT: Get wireless internet on busses, and
          blinds.
&lt;p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;
           
          Update. Implemented overrides on the ride home and still had
          time for another log entry. Writing code that actually works
          while riding on a bumpy bus with the hot sun glaring down on
          my monitor makes me feel kinda studly.....thats kinda sad ;-).
&lt;p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
          &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=Jackson%20Harper"&gt;I
          have finally overtaken the bull notes.&lt;/a&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F18%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F18%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Aug 2003: Going to Brazil</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today am flying to Brazil.  First stop will be Brasilia,
	for the Congress-sponsored event on &lt;a
	href="http://www.congresso.gov.br/softwarelivre"&gt;Free
	Software&lt;/a&gt;.

	Then am off to Porto Alegre to marry &lt;a
	href="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/images/bombon.jpg"&gt;Maria
	Laura&lt;/a&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F17%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F17%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Aug 2003: A purple dog that wears spats</title>
      <description>I always have fun looking at my sites referal URLs. My fav so
         far has been &lt;a
         href="http://statist.chungbuk.ac.kr/~ng/ng/zboard.php?id=talk"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
         there was a link to my site in that message board. No idea
         why.
         
         &lt;p&gt;
         
         Overall a pretty good day. Went for a hike, bought groceries,
         made tacos, did laundry, watched TV, and wrote some &lt;a
         href="http://lists.ximian.com/archives/public/mono-list/2003-August/015461.html"&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;.
         
         
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F17%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F17%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Aug 2003: New RSS feed</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After months of keeping on my TODO list `write a blog
	system', I gave up and wrote a small C# program to pull the
	existing messy files massage them and upload them to the site.
	Part of the problem is that I need something that will work in
	disconnected mode and let me use Emacs to compose these
	entries. 

	&lt;p&gt;I also gave up waiting for BlogX to be released: I like it,
	but the &lt;a
	href="http://www.gotdotnet.com/Community/Workspaces/Workspace.aspx?id=ddc98753-6559-489b-a533-57034790a93a"&gt;GotDotNet
	workspaces&lt;/a&gt; software is just horrible to use.  Even with
	Windows its horrible.

	&lt;p&gt;Microsoft still has some things to learn from the existing
	open source tools.

	&lt;p&gt;The next step is to write my own ASP.NET-based weblog
	system, but I have to overcome the the feeling of guilt
	everytime am not working on the core of Mono.
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F16%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F16%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Aug 2003: First Post</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        Seems like a good time to start a blog. Nice little app for
        rendering my entries provided by Miguel.
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        
        Worked out. In pretty bad shape, but I think I can change that
        pretty quickly. Now its time to rock ilasm overrides.
       
</description>
      <link>http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F16%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Jackson Harper</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://www.jacksonh.net/jackson/blog/all.html#08%2F16%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Aug 2003: My problems with C# and .NET</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love C# very much, and the new extensions that are being
	added to C# will improve the language in many areas:
	
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Iterators: they simplify authoring the
		IEnumerable/IEnumerator interfaces in a class.  Very
		nice.

		&lt;li&gt;Anonymous methods: reduce the glue required for
		small use cases.  For large cases, you dont want to
		use them anyways, as they make your code look ugly
		(remember: if a function does not fit on the screen,
		its probably buggy). 
	&lt;/ul&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Those will reduce the amount of coding required in some
	scenarios, but they do not address some of the most common
	problems that programmers face: strings and regular
	expressions.

	&lt;p&gt;.NET ships with a very powerful regex engine.  The engine
	is so powerful, that it is possible to use it to implement
	very advanced regexp-based applications.  Its as easy to use
	as the POSIX regex API is: slightly more verbose due to its OO
	heritage, but in general, very similar.

	&lt;p&gt;The problem is that there is no simple way of using this
	API from a language like C#: the developer is stuck with this
	low-level API.  Perl and Python both bundle powerful regular
	expression engines that are bound in a fairly usable way in
	the language.

	&lt;p&gt;Its a shame that C# does not have any simple way, or a nice
	syntactic sugar to manipulate this common idiom.

	&lt;p&gt;Strings manipulation in C# falls on the same category: some
	work was done, but it was not really completed.  Adding a few
	overloads to the class libraries would make C# a sweet
	language for string processing.

	&lt;p&gt;A two parameter indexer: string this [int start, int end]
	would clear a lot of the confussion with Substring arguments
	(a previous log entry has more details).
	
	&lt;p&gt;Although we could add this to Mono, the result would not be
	portable to .NET.

	&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is the Stream problem.  Reading a file in
	.NET involves two steps: opening the stream, and then creating
	a streamreader to read from it.  The code looks a bit like
	this:

&lt;pre&gt;
	Stream st = File.OpenRead ("notes.txt");
	StreamReader re = new StreamReader (st);
        string line;
			
	while ((line = re.ReadLine ()) != null)
		Console.WriteLine (line);
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Wouldn't it be nicer, if you could just do:

&lt;pre&gt;
	string line;
	while ((line = File.OpenRead ("notes.txt")) != null){
		Console.WriteLine (line);
	}
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The above could be easily implemented by having the
	FileStream implement IEnumerator as Guido does in Python.
	
	
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F15%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F15%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Aug 2003: Mono 0.26</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
	A new version of Mono has hit the streets.  This version is
	obviously the best Mono release ever.  A roadmap to Mono 1.0
	is also being prepared as we speak, for the joy of all the
	Mono users.
&lt;p&gt;
	Duncan surprised me on Sunday with a C# Cairo binding.  This
	was fast, and am really glad to see it happen so quickly.
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F14%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F14%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Aug 2003: Don Box in town.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
	Duncan and myself left the office early today to attend &lt;a
	href="http://www.gotdotnet.com/team/dbox/default.aspx?key=2003-08-15T12:39:29Z"&gt;Don's&lt;/a&gt;
	keynote at the XML web services conference.
&lt;p&gt;
	It was good to see Don, despite having taking a red eye the
	day before, he did an outstanding presentation on web services
	and showed some of the new features in C#.
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F13%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F13%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Aug 2003: Novell</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
	Went to Provo today to do a small presentation about Mono in
	an open session to Novell engineers.   It went pretty well,
	and I also got to talk with various developers about Novell's
	existing product line.
&lt;p&gt;
	Of particular interest are iFolder and NetMail
&lt;p&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F12%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F12%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Aug 2003: New apartment</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
	I signed my lease for my new apartment, which will be just a
	few blocks away from my current place.   Nat will be my neighbor.
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F10%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F10%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Aug 2003: New Chapter</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
        A fresh new chapter begins.
&lt;p&gt;
        More updates at &lt;a href="http://www.nat.org/2003/august"&gt;Nat's site&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        Two fantastic movies this weekend.  I just finished
        watching &lt;a href="http://us.imdb.com/Title?0207198"&gt;Was tun, wenn's
        brennt? &lt;/a&gt; which Laura recommended.  Yesterday Alex, Nat and
        myself went to see &lt;a
        href="http://us.imdb.com/Title?0283900"&gt;L'Auberge Espagnole&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;
        Maria Laura in Mexico:&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/images/bombon.jpg"&gt;
</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F04%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#08%2F04%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Jul 2003: VMs</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guido recently quoted a conversation we had about Parrot.
	I said to him that the Parrot VM design was based on ideology
	(Guido quoted me as saying religion ;-).  &lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite books is &lt;a
	href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/1558603298/ref=lib_dp_TFCV/103-7978374-1827822?v=glance&amp;s=books&amp;vi=reader#reader-link"&gt;Computer
	Architecture: A quantitative approach&lt;/a&gt;. 
	
	&lt;p&gt;The parrot design is based on ideology because some of the
	core design considerations are just that: `real machine use
	registers, hence register-based intermediate code is faster'.
	An ideology-based design is one where the design decisions are
	driven by punch lines and not by a careful and quantitative
	study of the problem at hand.  &lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Mono implements the .NET virtual execution system; This
	execution system uses a stack-based instruction set to
	&lt;i&gt;transport&lt;/i&gt; code.  Mono never actually sees the stack
	operations, because we treat the stack-based operations by
	their name: a serialization format for a tree representation
	of the original code.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;So for example, if you have an operation like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
		a = b + c;
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The code can be thought of as:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;img src="http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/images/Diagram1.png"&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;A possible serialization of this tree is easily expressed
	by a lisp-like expression:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
	(assign a (add b c))
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Another possible serialization is using bytecodes, for a
	stack machine&lt;/p&gt;:

&lt;pre&gt;
	ldloc b
	ldloc c
	add
	stloc a
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The above set of stack instructions can be easily decoded
	back into its original form (see drawing above).  This is what
	the Mono JIT does: it transforms its input CIL bytecodes into
	various trees like this (we call these the forest of trees):

&lt;pre&gt;
(stind.i4 regoffset[0xfffffff8(%ebp)] (add (ldind.i4 regoffset[0xfffffff4(%ebp)]) 
				      (ldind.i4 regoffset[0xfffffffc(%ebp)])))
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The above if the debugging output that renders our C-based
	trees.  We then use a code generator generator to transform
	the high-level operations (not listed in this example) into a
	list of low-level instructions:

&lt;pre&gt;
        1  loadi4_membase R9 &lt;- %ebp
        2  loadi4_membase R10 &lt;- %ebp
        3  add R8 &lt;- R9 R10 clobbers: 1
        4  move %eax &lt;- R8
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Depending on the optimizations turned on, there might be
	other steps involved, the end result is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
	mov    0x8(%ebp),%eax
	mov    0xc(%ebp),%ecx
	add    %ecx,%eax
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;(Actually, I had to trick the JIT compiler into doing this,
	because dead-code elimination and inlining in Mono eliminate
	redundant code).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Scripting languages&lt;/h4&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Now, am interested in this debate, because I think that
	Mono and the .NET VM are ideal virtual machines for scripting
	languages.  Since the .NET folks have done a fair ammount of
	work into the interop issues (The &lt;a
	href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/default.asp?url=/library/en-us/cpguide/html/cpconwhatiscommonlanguagespecification.asp"&gt;Common
	Language Specification&lt;/a&gt;) and it is a fairly advance virtual
	machine, my interest is making Mono a good host for those
	languages.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;It has been said `.NET works great for static languages,
	but not for scripting'.  Which is not true; VB.NET and JScript
	are both dynamic languages that happen to work just fine on
	the .NET Framework.  And we are convinced that the virtual
	machine can be improved.

	&lt;p&gt;The main issue we have today with Mono and scripting
	languages is that nobody has done a quantitatie study of what
	are the performance problems of running a dynamic language in
	the .NET/Mono CLR: Without an attempt to have a native
	compiler for the platform, and studying the problems, it is
	not possible to solve them. &lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;In one particular case (Lisp), we know that implementors
	will likely want to structure their code (or their generated
	code) like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
class Cell {
	Atom Head;
	Cell tail;
}

Method ()
{
	if (object is Cell){
		...
	} if (object is Atom){
		...
	}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;So what they need in this particular case is a fast
	implementation of the `is' operator (the `isinst'
	instruction).  For this, we did a &lt;a
	href="http://lists.ximian.com/archives/public/mono-list/2003-May/013897.html"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#07%2F22%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#07%2F22%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Jul 2003: Back!</title>
      <link>http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#07%2F13%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</link>
      <author>Miguel de Icaza</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="True">http://primates.ximian.com/~miguel/all.html#07%2F13%2F2003+12%3A00%3A00</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2003 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>